Keuntaek Lee

Email: keuntaek.lee@gatech.edu Website: keuntaeklee.github.io LinkedIn: keuntaeklee

Research Interests

My research interests are in the areas of robotics and machine learning. More specifically, my research centers around reinforcement learning, control theory, and computer vision. I study explainable artificial intelligence and safe learning based control algorithms for autonomous vehicles and robots.

EDUCATION

Georgia Institute of Technology

Atlanta, GA, USA

Ph.D. in Electrical and Computer Engineering, PI: Evangelos A. Theodorou

Aug. 2016–Dec. 2021 (Expected)

- Thesis: "Robust Deep Vision-based Control Algorithms with Probabilistic Learning"

Georgia Institute of Technology

Atlanta, GA, USA

M.S. in Electrical and Computer Engineering, PI: Evangelos A. Theodorou

Aug. 2016-Aug. 2018

Hanyang University B.S. in Electrical Engineering

Seoul, S. Korea Feb. 2009-Feb. 2016

- Summa Cum Laude

EXPERIENCE

Honda Research Institute, USA (HRI-US)

San Jose, CA, USA

Research Intern at ML and AI team

May. 2021-Aug. 2021

- Inverse Reinforcement Learning (IRL) and Control Research
- Implement state-of-the-art IRL and Model Predictive Control (MPC) algorithms
- Research and develop diverse behavior models conditioned on differences in human personality

Georgia Institute of Technology

Atlanta, GA, USA

Graduate Research Assistant at Autonomous Control and Decision Systems Lab.

Aug. 2016-Present

- AutoRally: Offroad Autonomous Driving
- AlphaPilot: Lockheed Martin AI Drone Racing Innovation Challenge
- Virtual Sully: Autopilot with Multilevel Adaptation for Handling Large Uncertainties

Honors and Awards

•	Amazon.com	Amazon Web Services Machine Learning Research Awards & Scholarship (75,000 USD)	2018 – 2019
•	RSS 2018	Finalist to Best Systems Paper Award	2018
•	South Korea	Government Scholarship to Study Abroad (80,000 USD)	2016-2018
•	Hanyang Univ.	Capstone Design Fair Best Award	2015
•	Hanyang Univ.	Techno-Business Capstone Design Best Award	2014
•	Hanyang Univ.	Dean's List & Scholarship	2013-2015

PUBLICATIONS

- [1] **K. Lee**, B. Vlahov, J. Gibson, J. M. Rehg, and E. A. Theodorou, "Approximate inverse reinforcement learning from vision-based imitation learning", in 2021 International Conference on Robotics and Automation (ICRA), Jun. 2021.
- [2] Z. Wang, O. So, **K. Lee**, and E. A. Theodorou, "Adaptive risk sensitive model predictive control with stochastic search", in 3rd Annual Learning for Dynamics and Control Conference (L4DC), Jun. 2021.
- [3] **K. Lee**, J. Gibson, and E. A. Theodorou, "Aggressive Perception-Aware Navigation using Deep Optical Flow Dynamics and PixelMPC", *IEEE Robotics and Automation Letters (RA-L)*, 2020.
- [4] **K. Lee**, G. N. An, V. Zakharov, and E. A. Theodorou, "Perceptual attention-based predictive control", 3rd Conference on Robot Learning (CoRL), 2019.
- [5] **K. Lee**, K. Saigol, and E. A. Theodorou, "Early failure detection of deep end-to-end control policy by reinforcement learning", in 2019 International Conference on Robotics and Automation (ICRA), May 2019, pp. 8543–8549.
- [6] K. Lee, Z. Wang, B. I. Vlahov, H. K. Brar, and E. A. Theodorou, "Ensemble bayesian decision making with redundant deep perceptual control policies", 18th IEEE International Conference on Machine Learning and Applications (ICMLA), 2019.
- [7] Y. Pan, C.-A. Cheng, K. Saigol, K. Lee, X. Yan, E. A. Theodorou, and B. Boots, "Imitation learning for agile autonomous driving", in *International Journal of Robotics Research (IJRR)*, 2019.
- [8] Z. Wang, K. Lee, M. A. Pereira, I. Exarchos, and E. A. Theodorou, "Deep forward-backward sdes for min-max control", The 58th IEEE Conference on Decision and Control (CDC), 2019.
- [9] G. Williams, B. Goldfain, **K. Lee**, J. Gibson, J. M. Rehg, and E. A. Theodorou, "Locally weighted regression psudo-rehearsal for adaptive model predictive control", 3rd Conference on Robot Learning (CoRL), 2019.
- [10] **K. Lee**, K. Saigol, and E. A. Theodorou, "Safe imitation learning for end-to-end control", in *Robotics:* Science and Systems (RSS) Workshop: Adversarial Robotics, 2018.
- [11] Y. Pan, C.-A. Cheng, K. Saigol, **K. Lee**, X. Yan, E. A. Theodorou, and B. Boots, "Agile autonomous driving using end-to-end deep imitation learning", in *Robotics: Science and Systems (RSS)*, 2018.
- [12] Y. Pan, C.-A. Cheng, K. Saigol, **K. Lee**, X. Yan, E. A. Theodorou, and B. Boots, "Deep autorally: Agile autonomous driving via end-to-end imitation learning", in *Robotics: Science and Systems (RSS) Workshop on Learning from Demonstrations in High-Dimensional Feature Spaces*, 2017.
- [13] Y. Pan, C.-A. Cheng, K. Saigol, K. Lee, X. Yan, E. A. Theodorou, and B. Boots, "Learning deep neural network control policies for agile off-road autonomous driving", in 2017 Conference on Neural Information Processing Systems (NeurIPS) Deep Reinforcement Learning Symposium, 2017.

PROJECTS

AutoRally: Safe AI-based off-road high-speed autonomous driving

Georgia Tech. Aug. 15. 2016–Present

- Developing ML-based algorithms and controllers for safe autonomous driving
- Funding sources: Amazon Web Services Machine Learning Research Awards, Komatsu Ltd.
- Keywords: Model Predictive Control, DDP, MPPI, Online Imitation Learning, Bayesian Neural Networks,
 Reinforcement Learning, Online model adaptation, Perceptual Control, Vision-based Control, Explainable AI
- Publications: 1 Journal, 5 Conferences, 3 Workshops

Virtual Sully: Autopilot with Multilevel Adaptation for Handling Large Uncertainties Georgia Tech.

Oct. 1. 2019–Present

- Developing ML-based autopilot systems for safe landing under uncertain situations
- Collaborative Research with UIUC
- Funding sources: NSF Award 1932288
- Keywords: Cyber Physical Systems, Costmap Learning
- Publications: 1 Conference

Deep Perceptual Adaptive Control for Safe Autonomy

Georgia Tech.

AlphaPilot: Lockheed Martin AI Drone Racing Innovation Challenge

Feb. 01. 2019–Dec. 06. 2019

- AlphaPilot Qualifier; Top 9 out of 430 teams worldwide
- Funding sources: NASA Langley Research Center Grant 80NSSC19M0211
- Keywords: Visual Servoing, MPPI, Object Detection, YOLO, Deep Optical Flow Dynamics, PixelMPC
- Publications: 1 Journal, 1 Conference

SKILLS

- Programming Languages: Python, C++, MATLAB Version Control: Git
- Deep Learning Tools: PyTorch, TensorFlow, Keras Operating Systems: Linux, Windows
- Robotics: ROS, MuJoCo, OpenAI Gym Cloud Computing: AWS

TEACHING

Georgia Institute of Technology

• Guest Lecturer in Robotics and Autonomy (AE4803)

Lectures on Differential Dynamic Programming and Model Predictive Control

Spring 2020, Fall 2020

• Teaching Assistant in Feedback Control Systems (ECE3550)

Spring 2019

ACADEMIC SERVICES

Reviewer

• IEEE Robotics and Automation Letters (RA-L)	2020, 2021
• IEEE International Conference on Robotics and Automation (ICRA)	2019, 2021
• IEEE Conference on Decision and Control (CDC)	2021
• IEEE/RSJ International Conference on Intelligent Robots and Systems (IROS)	2021
• Robotics: Science and Systems (RSS)	2019